Guide to the Jack Miles papers MS.F.045
Special Collections and Archives, University of California, Irvine Libraries
- Writings and editing, 1969-2021; Series 1.
  - Articles, essays, thesis, and reviews, 1969-2021; Subseries 1.2
    - Jacques Monod and the Cure of Souls, 1974 March (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - The Donkey and the Dog: Judaism and Islam at War, 1974 January 14 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Solzhenitsyn, Schoolbooks, and the American Decay, 1973 September (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - "The Wife of Onan and the Sons of Cain", National Review, 1973 August 17 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - "The Multi-colored Face of Pentecostalism", The Review of Books and Religion, 1973 June (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - "Beyond Nostalgia", Commonweal, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - IRAs Review, circa 1973 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - The Testaments of the Twelve Patriarchs, 1969 March 26 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Article index, undated (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Various writings, circa 1974-2015, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Grave Matters, 2003 (Box FB-020, Folder 10)
    - Claremont McKenna College, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 26)
      This folder contains articles written by Miles when he was scholar-in-residence at Claremont McKenna College, it includes some research files and correspondence. There is some research and correspondence included
    - "The Iraqi Dead", Commonweal, 2003 July 18 (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
    - Essays and speeches for University of California Press collection (unpublished), circa 1996-2002 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Iraq exit - New York Times, 2004-2007 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Research files, circa 1998-2008 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Australia, including "Waiting for the Preachers", 2010-2011 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Unpublished on Israel/Palestine, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished on The Satanic Verses, circa 1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Two representative vetting reports, 2008-2015 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Reviews of three Jesus-books, circa 1999-2007 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - The God of Abraham, Jesus, and Muhammad, circa 2003 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Undated writings (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - With His Power Unchecked, Michael Flynn Could Lead Trump into War with Iran, 2017 February 1 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "Embracing Ignorance: Jack Miles on His Path from Belief to Disbelief and Back" by Same Mowe, and "Why Religion Endures", The Sun, 2016 March (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - "'The Schooldays of Jesus': Coetzee's Teasing New Parable", The New York Times, 2017 February 24 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - "Rape, New Criticism, and the Humanities Core Course", UCI Magazine, Winter, 2017 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Why Are We Losing in the Middle East? Too Much STEM, Not Enough Humanities, 2015 May 1 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - "Self-Defense and Defense Against the Self", Dharma World, 2010 October-2010 December (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - "Trading Places: A Once-Catholic Episcopalian Looks at Benedict's Offer", Commonweal, 2010 January 10 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - "'The Evolution of God' by Robert Wright and 'The Case for God' by Karen Armstrong", Los Angeles Times, 2009 October 11 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - "After 'the War on Terror'", Commonweal, 2009 July 17 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - "Anglican Disunion", Commonweal, 2008 September 12 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Benedict XVI at the United Nations, 2008 April 22 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - "A Stirring at the Border", Commonweal, 2008 April 25 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Poetry as Nonfiction, 2007 November (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - "Kitsch en religie. Notities over de verloren ziel van de cultuur", Nexus, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Joseph's Bones by Jerome Segal review, Tikkun, 2007 July-2007 August (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - "Jesus of Nazareth by Joseph Ratzinger, Pope Benedict XVI", Commonweal, 2007 July 13 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - 'A Secular Age' by Charles Taylor and 'The Stillborn God' by Mark Lilla reviews, Los Angeles Times, 2007 September 16 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - "Preaching to the unconverted", Los Angeles Times book review, 2007 April 29 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - "AHR Conversations: Religious Identities and Violence", The American Historical Review, 2007 December (Box 11, Folder 43-44)
    - RAND, 2006 October (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - The Da Vinci Coda: Retrospective Reflections on a Pop Culture Phenomenon, 2006 August 14 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Time's Up", Los Angeles Times book review, 2006 August 20 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - "A Scientific Approach to Atheism", Washington Post, 2006 June 29 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "Judas and Jesus: What did the Gnostics really believe?", Commonweal, 2006 June 2 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Review of Breaking the Spell by Daniel C. Dennett, 2006 June 29 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "Judaist Israel, Islamist Palestine", Harvard Divinity Bulletin, Autumn, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "Suite deal has nuclear glow", LAtimes.com, 2005 September 4 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "A peace no one wins", LAtimes.com, 2005 August (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "Only Death Will Win", Los Angeles Times, 2005 June 25 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Imagine a Kosher Church, a review of Border Lines: The Partition of Judaeo-Christianity by Daniel Boyarin, published in Commonweal, 2005 October 17 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Israele come trovatello, Gesù come celibe. L'abbandono, l'adozione, la paternità di Dio, Che dite che io sia?, 2005 March (Box 12, Folder 15)
      The writing in this folder relates to speaking engagement material in Box 12 Folder 17.
    - "Israel as Foundling: Abandonment, Adoption, and the Fatherhood of God", offprint from Hebrew Studies Volume XLVI, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Myth of the Suppressing Church", Cross Currents, Summer, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Dr. Franklin D. Murphy memorial booklet with articles reprinted from the Los Angeles Times, including "Death in the L.A. Family", 1994 June 17 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Untitled Commonweal proof, 2018 March 23 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - "For the love of Earth, stop traveling", Washington Post, 2017 November (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Review of The Face of Water by Sarah Ruden in Commonweal, 2017 July 7 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - "What Would Baby Jesus Say? Nothing, of course", circa 2005 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - The Leisure of Worship and the Worship of Leisure, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - What Is Art For? A Meditation at the Getty Center (unpublished), undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - La discussion de George Steiner avec Dieu, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "A Gentile's Philip Roth", Commonweal, 2018 May 29 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "California Burning", Commonweal, 2018 January 2 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - "A Failed Apostle", Commonweal, 2018 March 23 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Thesis: Ancient Translations from Greek to Ethiopic and the Predictability of Translation Syntax, 1970 November (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Chet Grycz as I Remember Him, 2021 August (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - How to Argue About Religion and Never Lose, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Roosevelt Road story, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - How Firm a Foundation? World Religions and the Quest for Closure, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Coming of Age in Chicago: a review of An Unfinished Season by Ward Just, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - The Art Photography of Janet Sternburg, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Review of God: An Anatomy by Francesca Stavrakopoulou, 2021 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "The Paradox of Pluralism", Commonweal, 2019 November (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "With God, Bush is on the Right Side", Los Angeles Times, 2003 December (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - A Roadmap to Qur'ans in English, 2017 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Mass. Luis Vriarte Lopez, Saint Teresa parish, 2019 June (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Review of Religion in Human Evolution, from the Paleolithic to the Axial Age by Robert N. Bellah, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Endpapers, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - A Modest Proposal for Resolving the American Immigration Crisis (unpublished), 1976, 2017-2020 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - The Norton Anthology of World Religions (NAWR), 1984-2017; 2003-2017; Subseries 1.3
    This subseries consists of material collected by Miles as the general editor of The Norton Anthology of World Religions, which was published in 2014. The anthology "offers a portable library of more than 1,000 primary texts from the world's major religions: Hinduism, Buddhism, and Daoism (Volume 1); and Judaism, Christianity, and Islam (Volume 2)". The folders contain drafts, revisions, and proofs; correspondence; an evaluation as Distinguished Professor for University of California, Irvine with documentation on the anthology; contracts with all seven scholars including Miles; preliminary outlines and key documents; guidelines and reports; information about the companion website; a Getty program linked to the anthology that Miles appeared at; reviews and responses; talk notes; research files; and ideas for a blog and companion textbook that were not used. Many of the folders include notes about the material written by Miles in 2017.
    - NAWR - Christianity revisions and condensation, 2009-2013 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - NAWR in gestation - Miles' 5 year review, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Daoism section introductions, early and final, 2012-2014 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - Robson, Dao, Table of Contents, correspondence, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Early correspondence on NAWR Table of Contents, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Islam: revised Table of Contents and list of additions/subtractions, 2009 August (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Buddhism - final Table of Contents, 2009 August (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Judaism - final Table of Contents, 2009 August (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Hinduism: revised Table of Contents with final adds and drop, 2009 August (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - NAWR - Contents pages, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - NAWR - three key documents, 2003-2009 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - NAWR - companion website, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - NAWR - first serial excerpts, 2012-2014 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - NAWR - Getty program, J. Miles and D. Biale, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - NAWR - Hindu, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - NAWR - acknowledgments, dedications and epigraphs, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - NAWR - introduction, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Shortened introduction for paperback (6-vol) college edition, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - NAWR - Islam, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - NAWR - Christianity correspondence and proofs with corrections, 2013-2014 (Box 2, Folder 6-10)
    - Norton Anthology correspondence, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Norton Anthology correspondence and reviews, 2014-2015 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - NAWR talk notes, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - NAWR reviews and letters, 2014-2015 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Research files guide, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Research files: Untitled by David O'Reilly and correspondence, circa 1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Research files: altruism, aspects of, and religion, 2008-2013 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Research files: art and religious experience, 2009-2013 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Research files: CERN, 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Research files: China, 2011-2013 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Research files: Christianity, aspects of, 2006-2010 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Research files: cognitive science of religion, 2002-2013 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Research files: cosmology and dark matter, 2009-2013 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Research files: definition of religion, 1984-2013 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Research files: evolution and religion, 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Research files: globalization, 2004-2012 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Research files: history of the subject of religion, 2008-2013 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Research files: literature, 2010-2012 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Research files: leads not followed, 2007-2009 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Research files: brooding, raising, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Research files: miscellany from introduction, 2011-2015 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Research files: opposition to religion, 2005-2013 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Research files: practical benefits of religion, 2004-2013 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Research files: secularism, 2010-2011 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Research files: science and religion, 2003-2013 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Reply to reviews of NAWR, 2016-2017 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Material related to the launch of Norton Anthology of World Religions, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Various NAWR, 2005-2006 (Box 10, Folder 21-23)
    - Various NAWR, 2008-2009 (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
    - A bright idea that didn't work for NAWR, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - NAWR - Buddhism, Daoism, and problems en route, 2008-2011 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - NAWR - two exchanges about Islam, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - NAWR - serial publication in Atlantic and Moment, 2014-2015 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Norton textbook, circa 2002-2009 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - NAWR/christianity - correspondence about introduction and contents with hand-annotated proofs, 2008-2011 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Reviews of NAWR, 2015-2016 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Norton Anthology of World Religions draft, 2014 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Contributions, collaborations, and editorial committees, 1979-2017; Subseries 1.4
    This subseries consists of writings Miles contributed to other people's books, such as introductions and forewords; collaborations, most notably with artist Lisa Ruyters when he provided text to accompany her work, "Stations of the Cross"; and material related to his time on the editorial committee of University of California Press. Some of the folders contain correspondence, research and reference files, photographs and negatives, publicity, and notes by Miles in 2017 providing more context to the material.
    - J. Harold Ellens, The Apostles' Creed, afterword by Jack Miles, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Best American Spiritual Writing, introduction, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Orientation at University of California Press, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Foreword to The Monk and the Philosopher, 1999 February (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Foreword to Le coin du voile, 1997 January 7 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - With Lisa Ruyter, Stations of the Cross, circa 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Lisa Ruyter, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Stations: Ruyter - Miles, 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Religion, Identity and Global Governance book chapter, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Foreword to Confessions: A New Translation by Peter Constantine, 2017 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - "Poetry to the People", Introductions and Tributes: Three Decades booklet by Joel Conarroe, 2018 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - "Poetry to the People", 2020 Vision: Friends in Focus booklet by Joel Conarroe (Box 15, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, 1960-2021; Series 2.
  This series consists of correspondence to and from Jack Miles in both a professional and personal capacity. The majority of the general correspondence, which consists of letters to Jack Miles, is made up of letters of congratulations when he won the Pulitzer Prize in 1996 for God: A Biography. It also includes a letter from President Bill Clinton in 1997 (Box 8, Folder 8), and letters from President Joe Biden and Congressman Adam Schiff in 2020-2021 (Box 15, Folder 30). There is also a run of letters sent by Jack Miles to politicians, colleagues, and family members. There are individual folders for certain correspondents that Miles singled out - most notably Philip Roth (who also appears in the general correspondence/letters sent) and his biographer, Blake Bailey; the poet Todd Boss; philosopher Mark C. Taylor; painter Frederick Franck and his son Lukas Franck; and philosopher George Dennis O'Brien. The series also contains a chronological file of correspondence from Miles' time as a professor at UCI, as well as early letters sent by Miles to his family in the early 1960s from Ohio while he was studying at Xavier University and Europe while he was studying at the Pontifical Gregorian University in Rome. Some of the correspondence contains writings of others that Miles critiqued or edited, as well as notes written by Miles in 2017 to give the correspondence more context.
  The series is physically arranged in its original order.
  - Jack Miles and Philip Roth, 1977-2016 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Todd Boss, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mark C. Taylor, 2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Website/Eric David, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Book/manuscript critiques, 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - JackMiles.com, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, 1994-2016, undated (Box 8, Folder 1-16)
    Folder 8 includes a letter from President Bill Clinton in 1997.
  - Letters sent, 1981-2016, undated (Box 8, Folder 17-21, Box 9, Folder 1-5)
  - Chronological University of California, Irvine, 2007-2015 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Foreign correspondence, circa 1997-2002 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - George Dennis O'Brien correspondence, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Blake Bailey about Philip Roth, with correspondence between Miles and Roth, circa 1989-2017 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Noteworthy letters, 2005-2017 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Letters sent, 2017-2018 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Letters from Jack Miles to his family, 1960-1965 (Box 12, Folder 39-40)
  - Frederick Franck and son Lukas Franck, 2018 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Frederick Franck, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Letter to David Karl re: proposal for a five-part series, "Contested Identities: Religion vs. Nation in Four Theaters of Conflict", 2007 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Letter from the Chicago Province of the Society of Jesus, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - General correspondence, 2017-2021 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    Includes letters from President Joe Biden and Congressman Adam Schiff.
  - Letters sent, 2019-2021 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Letters from Philip Roth booklet from Joel Conarroe, 2019 (Box 15, Folder 35)
- Teaching materials, 1966-2017; Series 3.
  This series consists of teaching materials from the various colleges Miles has taught at, including UCI, Occidental College, Loyola University of Chicago, and Claremont Graduate University. Materials include class notes and slides; syllabi; faculty profiles; correspondence; exam questions; notes for courses never taught; memorabilia related to Miles' involvement as judge, jury chair, and director of the Kingsley Tufts Poetry Awards program at Claremont Graduate University; and information about the Chairs controversy at UCI. Many of the folders include notes written by Miles in 2017 to give more context to the materials.
  - Claremont Graduate University, School of Religion, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Occidental/Gen, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - RS280 "The Character of God", 2005 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Multi-campus Research Group on Theology, Philosophy and Politics, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Various teaching materials, circa 1996-2010 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    This folder contains materials originally from folders titled "misc. rec'd", "chron." and "ipse" related to his teaching career.
  - Iliad - Humanities Core, Fall, 2015-2016 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 30 Years War - Humanities Core, Fall, 2015-2016 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Religion and Ecology course, Spring, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Tufts Board of Directors, 1993-1999 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Tufts Memorabilia, 1993-2001 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Theo Lit, circa 1970-1975 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Character of God, Occidental, 1999-2006 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Fictions of Faith, University of California, Irvine, Spring, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Prose, Poetry and the English Bible, University of California, Irvine, Winter, 2012 (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Theory and Method in R.S., University of California, Irvine, Spring, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - God: A Literary Introduction (GALI), University of California, Irvine, Spring, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Religious Studies 5A, World Religions I, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Bible from Scratch, notes for a course never taught, 1966-1975 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Humanities Core Course - lecture notes, study questions, and instructor keys, 2010-2013 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Humanities Core Course - lecture notes and support materials, 2010-2013 (Box 11, Folder 19-21)
  - Religious Studies at UC Irvine annual newsletter, Summer, 2017 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - University of California, Irvine Religious Studies transition Sikh and Jain Chairs, 2015-2016 (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
  - University of California, Irvine Hinduism Chair (Thakkar), 2013-2014 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Dharma Civilization Foundation and Dharma Civilization Foundation Chair, 2013-2015 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Chairs controversy, 2015-2016 (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
  - Qur'an course, 2015 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Speaking engagements, 1975-2021; Series 4.
  This series contains material related to speaking engagements Jack Miles participated in. Materials include drafts and transcripts of talks at conferences and symposiums; transcripts of interviews on NPR; lecture notes; research files; previously unpublished remarks, and audiovisual material. The series also contains information from when Miles was asked to speak at UCI commencement in 2008 but also asked to by the union American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees due to striking service employees. Miles wrote an op-ed in support of the strikers and a fair contract, and collected correspondence and other related material. He also spoke at a UC Regents Meeting about the negotiations in September 2008. The folders include his canceled commencement address, correspondence, newspaper articles, court documents, information from AFSCME, information related to a UC regents meeting, and notes. Many of the folders in the series contain notes by Miles in 2017 to give the materials more context.
  - University of California, Irvine commencement, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University of California v. American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Claremont Graduate School-Loyola Marymount University, 2006 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Conversation with Louis Begley on Wartime Lies, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Remarks/Symposium (1 of 2): "Ethics of the Neighbor", Symposium, University of California, Los Angeles, 2004 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Remarks/Symposium (2 of 2): Muslim Public Affairs Council - remarks, 2004 December 18 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - NPR interview transcripts, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Remarks (mostly), circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - The Disarmament of God, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Introduction to a Discussion of El Niño, 2003 March 8 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - O Grave, Where is Thy Victory?, 2002 November 8 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - How God Led, 2002 October 15 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 9/11 Homily, 2002 September 11 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Faith, Fanaticism, and the Environment, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Various speaking engagements, circa 1995-2016, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    This folder contains materials originally from folders titled "misc. rec'd", "chron." and "ipse" related to various speaking engagements.
  - George Segal/Skirball, 1996-2017; 1996-1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hillel House speech and University of California, Irvine speech, 2011-2012 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Remarks on Howard Wettstein's The Significance of Religious Experience, 2011-2013 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Three representative public talks, 2003-2007 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Lesson of Joseph's Bones, Commencement Address at American Jewish University, 2008 May 18 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - The Christ of Mere Literature (unpublished), 2006 November (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Religion and American Foreign Policy, Arizona State University (unpublished), 2006 October 25 (Box 12, Folder 3)